rootsrated.com 2017-02-11

# Privacy Policy

This privacy policy applies to all visitors to or users of RootsRated’s applications, websites, products and services. Please read this privacy policy carefully. By setting up an account with us or accessing our website or application, you agree to this privacy policy. If you do not agree, do not set up an account or access our website or application. You are welcome to contact us if you have any questions.

**We collect but do not link personal and activity data.**

We use technologies like cookies (small files stored by your browser), web beacons, or unique device identifiers to anonymously identify your computer or device so we can deliver a better experience. Our systems also log information like your browser, operating system and IP address.

We also may collect personally identifiable information that you provide to us, such as your name, address, phone number or email address. With your permission, we may also access other personal information on your device, such as your phone book, calendar or messages, in order to provide services to you. If authorized by you, we may also access profile and other information from services like Facebook.

Our systems are not designed to associate personal information with your activities (such as pages you view or things you click on or search for).

We do not knowingly contact or collect personal information from children under 13. If you believe we have inadvertently collected such information, please contact us so we can promptly obtain parental consent or remove the information.

Our service does not currently recognize the “Do Not Track” signal that may be available in some web browsers.

**We may collect and share anonymous location data.**

To customize our service for you, we and our partners may collect, use, and share precise location data, including the real-time geographic location of your computer or device. This location data is collected anonymously in a form that does not personally identify you and is used only to provide and improve our service. We may obtain your consent on your first use of the service.

**You can request to see your personal data.**

You can sign into your account to see any personally identifiable information we have stored, such as your name, email, address or phone number. You can also contact us by email to request to see this information.

**We keep personal data until you delete it.**

We remove personally identifiable information (such as your name, address, email or phone number) and other preferences associated with your account promptly after you delete your account. We may retain other data indefinitely.

**We don’t share your personal information with marketers.**

We generally do not share personally identifiable information (such as name, address, email or phone) with other companies for marketing purposes.

**Ad companies collect anonymous data. You can opt out.**

Ad companies may use and collect anonymous data about your interests to customize content and advertising here and in other sites and applications. Interest and location data may be linked to your device, but is not linked to your identity. Click to see company privacy policies and opt-out choices:

Google
    “Google (www.google.com) operates the Google Display Network (comprising partner websites and some Google properties like YouTube), DoubleClick online ad serving products and the DoubleClick Ad Exchange, and Invite Media. These provide advertisers with the tools needed to plan, execute and analyze marketing programs with greater ease and efficiency, while enabling publishers to maximize their returns from online advertising. Note: Because Google uses DoubleClick and Invite technology, cookies placed by Google for behavioral advertising, including the opt out cookie, will appear as DoubleClick and Invite cookies.”

**You can ask privacy questions.**

If you have any questions or concerns about our privacy policies, please contact us:

501 East 16th Street, Unit 5,  
Chattanooga, TN 37408 

**Service providers access data on our behalf.**

In order to serve you, we may share your personal and anonymous information with other companies, including vendors and contractors. Their use of information is limited to these purposes, and subject to agreements that require them to keep the information confidential. Our vendors provide assurance that they take reasonable steps to safeguard the data they hold on our behalf, although data security cannot be guaranteed.

Analytics companies may access anonymous data (such as your IP address or device ID) to help us understand how our services are used. They use this data solely on our behalf. They do not share it except in aggregate form; no data is shared as to any individual user. Click to see company privacy policies that govern their use of data:

Google Analytics
    “Google Analytics is a web analytics tool that helps website owners understand how visitors engage with their website. Google Analytics customers can view a variety of reports about how visitors interact with their website so they can improve it. Google Analytics collects information anonymously. It reports website trends without identifying individual visitors.”

**We take steps to protect personal information.**

We take reasonable steps to secure your personally identifiable information against unauthorized access or disclosure. We encrypt transmission of data on pages where you provide payment information. However, no security or encryption method can be guaranteed to protect information from hackers or human error.

Information we collect may be stored or processed on computers located in any country where we do business.

**Special situations may require disclosure of your data.**

To operate the service, we also may make identifiable and anonymous information available to third parties in these limited circumstances: (1) with your express consent, (2) when we have a good faith belief it is required by law, (3) when we have a good faith belief it is necessary to protect our rights or property, or (4) to any successor or purchaser in a merger, acquisition, liquidation, dissolution or sale of assets. Your consent will not be required for disclosure in these cases, but we will attempt to notify you, to the extent permitted by law to do so.

**You can review more privacy-related information.**

We reserve the right to modify this privacy policy from time to time at our sole discretion. This privacy policy was last updated on July 28, 2014. Our privacy policy may change from time to time. It is your responsibility to review our privacy policy from time to time to ensure that you continue to agree with our privacy policy. If you no longer agree to this privacy policy after a modification, you must immediately cease using our website and application. If we make any material changes to our privacy policy, that materially affect registered users, we will send registered users a notice by email, push notification or text.
